Ebaad Ali

6 years of hands-on coding. I have a resourceful and hard-working personality and experienced in object-oriented programming, web development, and working in an Agile environment. I quickly learn and master new technologies while setting a progressive team and self-directed directive.

Toronto, Ontario
416-566-8510
ebaadali@gmail.com
http://www.ebaadali.com

EXPERIENCE

Cell-Mate — Junior Software Architect

March 2018 - March 2019

A system to manage their finances, employee stats, and inventory PHP, CSS, BOOTSTRAP, MYSQL, AZURE

- Produced UML and Use-Case Diagrams following requirements and requisitions to implement on Azure
- Developed the User Dashboard and ensured security was consistent in application.
- Efficiently worked in an Agile environment with other developers co-ordinating with GitHub.

J'Adore — Junior Software Developer

October 2017 – October 2018

Inventory Manager and Point of Sale System
ASP .NET (MVC), MYSQL, AZURE, CSS, BOOTSTRAP, C#

- Fixed a critical database design error that was causing a lot of lost time
- Designed the landing page and overall flow of web-app.
- Implemented roles to create a dynamic and secure web-app

Justo Tellez — Junior Web Developer

March 2016 - September 2016

Website to spread the message of P-Flag HTML5, CSS3, JQUERY, JAVASCRIPT, PHP, TWITTER/INSTAGRAM API

- Ensured full functionality of various social media APIs in order to enable synchronized logins, content sharing features, and other forms of backlink generation in a seamless end-user process.
- Collaborated towards appealing and professional web design.
- Demonstrated excellent coordination and dependability

SKILLS

Project Leadership

Database Development

Object-Oriented Applications

Software Development Life Cycle

Web Development

Client Engagement

Framework Management

Development Strategy

UI & UX Design

TECHNICAL ACUMEN

HTML5 | JavaScript | PHP |
CSS | TypeScript | jQuery | C |
C++ | Java | Python | Bash |
UNIX | ASP.NET | Angular |
Bootstrap | Django | React |
Node | Express | SQL | MySQL |
noSQL | mongoDB | Oracle
SQL | MATLAB | Assembler |
IBMi | Android | CLI

EDUCATION

Seneca College, Toronto — Diploma Computer Programmer and Analyst

JANUARY 2016 - APRIL 2019

- Demonstrated strong capabilities in a variety of object-oriented, web development, and mobile development
- Applied knowledge of design methods and implementation to create effective and scalable code for diverse end-user needs.
 Experienced in software development lifecycle including user needs analysis, design, implementation, testing, documentation, and support with ability to work in Agile environments.
- Worked effectively in interdisciplinary settings to collect and analyze user needs and stories, interpreting expectations into design and development goals to ensure quality deliverables.
 Coordinates professionally with internal and external stakeholders throughout the development process.